I also sculpt in wood.
And wood is probably one of the oldest forms of sculpture.
I mean it doesn't... if the civilization were to die and the wood ends up on the ground you're not going to find it.
There are very primitive wood sculptures that are found. I mean my work, actually, I consider kind of primitive because, I don't know, I drew a lot of my concepts from ester island.
I love these tall slender pieces that I do.
And the question is how to preserve it.
Today we have much better ways of preserving it.
And I love working with wood also because it's just so organic.
And today I'm going to demonstrate how I sculpt in wood.
In the northwest area of the United States here the people do totem poles.
The do different totems in other countries also that represent families.
And now that I have the log, I'm going to take my sketch book and put down what I think I want to create with this piece.
So I get my sketch book, open it up.
I was inspired by my wife's father, who was a war hero.
And when he passed away, I decided I was going to do a war memorial piece.
And I'm going to name it Eternal Hero.
All is basically is is this: I'm going to follow the line of the sculpture.
I'm going to follow the line of the log or the tree.
And my sketches are very simple.
I want the arms to come up like this.
I do very simple sketches.
And it's not uncommon for me to use a lot of little squirrels to get the shape of the body.
And I want the legs to go down like this.
And then he's going to have a medal of honor up here.
To bring the energy to the piece, I will put gold leaf on the faces, gold leaf on the faces and on the hands and on the medal.
And the piece will be painted to make it look like bronze.